When we design an algorithm to classify objects and
当我们设计算法来分类对象和图片时
images we have to deal with a lot of irrelevant information.
我们需要处理大量的不相关信息
We really only want our algorithm to
我们只是希望算法能判断
determine if an object is present in the image or not.
图片中是否存在某个对象
The size of the object doesn't matter neither does the angle.
对象的大小和角度并不重要
Or if I move it all the way to the right side of the image,
或者对象是否跑到了图片的右侧
it's still an image with an avocado.
依然是一张牛油果图片
In other words, we can say that we want our algorithm to
换句话说 我们希望算法能学习
learn an invariant representation of the image.
图片的不变表示
We don't want our model to change its prediction based on the size of the object.
我们不希望模型根据对象的大小而改变预测
This is called scale invariance.
这叫做标度不变性
Likewise, we don't want the angle of the object to matter.
类似地 我们不希望对象的角度造成影响
This is called rotation invariance.
这叫做旋转不变性
If I shift the image a little to the left or to
如果我向左或向右稍微移动图片
the right well it's still an image with an avocado,
依然是牛油果图片
and this is called translation invariance.
这叫做平移不变性
CNNs do have some built in translation invariance.
CNN 具有一些内置的平移不变性
To see this, you'll need to first recall how we calculate max pooling layers.
为此 你需要首先回忆下我们是如何计算最大池化层的
Remember that at each window location,
在每个窗口位置
we took the maximum of the pixels contained in the window.
我们都获取窗口中最大的像素
This maximum value can occur anywhere within the window.
这个最大值会出现在窗口中的任何位置
The value of the max pooling node would be the same,
最大池化层节点的值可能是相同的
if we translated the image a little to the left, to the right,
如果我们将图片向左、右、上、下平移
up, down as long as the maximum value stays within the window.
只要最大值保持在窗口中 节点的值就可能相同
The effect of applying many max pooling layers in a sequence,
在每个卷积层后面紧跟着一个最大池化层地
each one following a convolutional layer
应用很多最大池化层的效果是
is that we could translate the object quite far to the left,
我们能将对象平移到最左侧
to the top of the image,
最上方 最底部
to the bottom of the image and still our network will be able to make sense of it all.
神经网络依然能理解该图片吗？
This is truly a non-trivial problem.
这真的是一个不可忽视的问题
Recall that the computer only sees a matrix of pixels.
计算机只看到一个像素矩阵
And transforming an object scale, rotation,
变换对象的大小 旋转角度 在图片中的位置
or position in the image has a huge effect on the pixel values.
对像素值有很大的影响
We, as humans, can see the difference in images quite
作为人类 我们可以非常清晰地看出图片中的区别
clearly but how do you think you do
但是如果只给出对应的数组数字
if you were just given the corresponding array of numbers.
该怎么区别呢
Thankfully, there's a technique that works well for
幸运的是 有一种技巧
making our algorithms more statistically invariant,
可以很好地让算法更加具有统计不变性
but it will feel a little bit like cheating.
但是感觉有点像在欺骗
The idea is this,
原理是
if you want your CNN to be rotation invariant,
如果要 CNN 具有旋转不变性
well then you can just add some images to your training set
那么可以向训练集中添加一些图片
created by doing random rotations on your training images.
这些图片对训练图片进行随机旋转
If you want more translation invariance,
如果希望具有平移不变性
you can also just add new images created
那么可以通过随机地平移训练图片
by doing random translations of your training images.
向训练集中添加新的图片
When we do this, we see that we have expanded the training set by augmenting the data.
这么做时 我们通过增强数据扩展了数据集
Data augmentation will also help us to avoid overfitting.
数据增强还可以帮助我们避免过拟合
This is because the model is seeing many new images.
这是因为模型看到了很多新的图片
Thus, it should be better at generalizing
因此应该更能够广义化
and we should get better performance on the test dataset.
测试集中的效果应该更好
Let's augment the training data and see if our 10 data
我们增强训练集 看看上个视频中的 10 个数据集
set from the previous video and see if we can improve our test accuracy.
看看是否能够改善测试准确率
We'll be using a Jupyter notebook that you can download below.
我们将使用可在下方下载的 Jupyter notebook
After importing the data,
导入数据后
we import a python class called ImageDataGenerator.
我们导入一个 python 类 叫做 ImageDataGenerator
This class will do all of the augmentation for us.
该类将帮助我们完成所有增强工作
We just need to tell it what kind of augmentation we want.
我们只需告诉它我们想要什么样的增强
In this line of code,
在这行代码中
I create an augmented image generator that
我创建了一个增强图片生成器
will randomly shift my images vertically and horizontally.
它将随机地水平和垂直移动图片
It will also randomly horizontally flip my images.
还会随机地水平翻转图片
Now that the configuration is specified,
指定配置后
I need to fit it to my data.
需要添加到我的数据中
Let's see what some of these augmented images look like.
我们看看其中一些增强图片的效果
We'll visualize augmentations of
我们将只可视化前 12 张训练图片的增强效果
only the first 12 training images which I've stored in the array extreme subset.
我将其存储在了 x_train_subset 数组中
We now just need to call the flow function.
现在只需调用 flow 函数
We'll get more into the details of that in a few minutes.
稍后我们将详细了解该函数
For now, let's check out the outputted augmented images.
暂时先看看输出的增强图片
Try to match them to their corresponding original image.
试着将它们匹配到相应的原始图片
Can you see how the augmented images have been created?
可以看出增强图片是如何创建的吗？
Which ones have been shifted and which have been flipped?
哪些图片平移了 哪些翻转了
Before using these augmented images,
在使用这些增强图片之前
we'll need to define our CNN architecture.
我们需要定义我们的 CNN 架构
We'll use the model from the previous video.
我们将使用上个视频中的模型
We'll compile the model as before.
和之前一样编译该模型
But now when we go to fit our CNN to the augmented training data,
但是现在当我们用增强训练数据拟合 CNN 时
the commands are a little bit different.
命令有点不同了
The training step looks mostly the same except for three differences.
训练步骤几乎一样 但是有三点区别
First, fit has been changed to fit generator.
首先 fit 变成了 fit_generator
Whenever you're fitting your CNN augmented images that
只要拟合通过 ImageDataGenerator 类
are being generated by the ImageDataGenerator class,
生成的 CNN 增强图片
you always change the fit command to fit_generator.
就始终需要将 fit 命令改成 fit_generator
Second in place of the training data we have
其次 在训练集中
this flow command that has been executed on our training set.
我们对训练集执行了这个 flow 命令
It makes the data generator create batches of augmented images.
它使数据生成器创建一批批增强图片
Remember that we visualized one of these batches in the previous step in the notebook.
我们在 notebook 中的上一步可视化了其中一个批次
You'll always pass in the train set with
你将始终传入训练集和对应的标签
the corresponding labels along with the number of images that you want in a batch.
以及批次中的图片数量
Third, we're required to specify a variable that encodes the number of steps per epoch.
第三 我们需要指定一个变量 表示每个 epoch 的步长数量
It's typically set to the number of unique samples in a set divided by the batch size.
通常设为数据集中的唯一样本数量除以批次大小
By running this code so,
通过运行这段代码
we can train the model.
我们可以训练模型
And we load the weights that got the best validation accuracy.
加载验证准确率最高的权重
When we test the model,
当我们测试该模型时
we get a test accuracy of over 68 percent.
测试准确率超过了 68%
This is an improvement over the model we trained without augmentation in the last video.
与上个视频中没有增强图片的模型相比 有了改进
In fact, augmentation is used extensively in
实际上 现实中经常会使用增强处理
real world applications to boost the performance of CNN models.
来改善 CNN 模型的效果